# Jason Semerau

Director of IT / System Administrator / Helpdesk Manger

Las Vegas, NV 89147 Jason@TracksideExp.com 9493106796

My goal is to obtain employment in a Lead or Internal Team role to further my career where my abilities, skills and talent can be fully applied to achieve top results. I feel my extensive experience places me ahead of most candidates. Half of my past 20 years have been working in a Senior Management/Executive support roles for major Corporations. Being very "Hands-on" has helped create cohesive IT teams for me in the past. I also host a local talk show further exercising my communication skills.

\*Authorized to work in the US for any employer

## Work Experience:

#### **Director of IT**

Coldwell Banker - West Coast

2019 to 2020

- · Configured Exchange server and user accounts
- Implemented IT Dept. Inventory control of PC's/Parts/Software
- Provided Support for Senior Level Management
- Maintained 500+ Field Agents
- Configured outside sales reps laptops: IBM ThinkPad/Dell Latitude/Toshiba Satellite
- · Established policies and procedures
- Phone system Management 3cx
- IT Managed Solutions for remote staff
- Daily managed network backups and switches (3560, etc.) CAN
- Logistic coordination
- Configured 2000, 2012 Exchange server and user accounts via AD & Azure
- Implemented IT Dept. Inventory control of PC's/Parts/Software

## **System Administrator**

MMA Specialties - Las Vegas, NV

2015 to 2019

- Developed Marketing Strategies and implemented marketing goals
- Set up and configured all new hires and sales reps.
- Managed all IT Expansion Projects
- Maintained 300+users on ACD call center software
- Configured outside sales reps laptops: IBM ThinkPad/Dell Latitude/Toshiba Satellite
- Developed Bar code scanning of loan files for control of appraisal flow
- · Daily managed network using Windows Servers
- Configured Exchange server and user accounts
- Office 365 Management
- Implemented IT Dept. Inventory control of PC's/Parts/Software
- Provided Support for Senior Level Management
- Extensive Networking Application Knowledge: CSRM-FIM-CNA-Fuze
- Implemented Crystal Reports for internal tracking and progress reporting
- Installed OS and configured workstations- laptops/desktop/servers
- Helpdesk support management- Drivers, hardware R&R, backups

## **Operations Administrator**

Genesis Renewable Energy - Laguna Beach, CA 2010 to 2015

- Managed a Team who maintained 100% functionality of network environment for over 150 users
- Team installed OS and configured workstations- Laptops/desktop/servers
- Fully Versed in all Windows OS & proficient with Apple OSX

<sup>\*</sup>Prior Security Clearance

- Beta tested Windows and implemented them to Developers
- Team Managed Cisco Network Routers & T-1 telecom network
- Helpdesk team support management- Drivers, hardware R&R, backups
- Maintained functionality of all Printers
- Daily managed network using Windows Servers, CSRM, Office 365 Admin
- Configured Exchange server and user accounts AD-Azure
- Implemented IT Dept. Inventory control of PC's/Parts/Software
- Provided Support for Senior Level Management
- Implemented Crystal Reports for internal ticket tracking and progress reporting
- · Ability to establish long term report with diverse suppliers and support
- · Manage and maintain Helpdesk staff nationwide and abroad
- Heavy External Team Management- consistently over 500 reps.
- · Configured remote users using/PC anywhere/logmein.com/windows remote desktop utility
- Establish and maintained network for Networked security systems

#### **Network Administrator**

MedAvant - Santa Ana, CA 2003 to 2010

- Advanced DNS knowledge including Active Directory integrated DNS and BIND management
- Coordinated the deployment and installation of over 100 Windows clients in a workgroup environment, performed the migration to a single Windows domain network with 2 Domain
- Provided break fix support for all hardware and software issues via in-person, phone, or remote control administration tools.
- Evaluated and created the assembly processes for New Hardware distribution nationwide
- Installed and configured settings of multiple Cisco switches(3560) in various centers & various
- Designing and deploying new server/client hardware and software enhancements.
- Physical server management including Dell and HP hardware management Active Directory and Azure.

## Education

## **Computer learning Center** MCSE / A+

Irvine, CA 1996

#### Skills

- Information Technology
- Desktop Support
- Help Desk
- Network Administration

## Assessments

Mechanical Skills: Aptitude — Proficient

1990-2019

**Publications** 

**Trackside Experience** 

http://TracksideExp.com March 2010-Ongoing

Company and Talk Show, Established 2010